

JIM COURTOIS

314.677.0911

thatonejimguy@gmail.com www.thatonejimguy.com

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a full-time creative position that challenges me to further develop my technical skills.

ABOUT

I am a St. Louis Native with over 7 years of experience in design. The bulk of my career has been spent as an in-house designer creating all types of brand assets. Over the last 2+ years I have been focused almost completely on front-end web development and mobile app design. I have created several websites using tools like Twitter Bootstrap, SASS, WordPress, and jQuery libraries. I am also fluent in standard design practices for the iOS and Android mobile platforms.

TECHNICAL SKILLS			
 Photoshop 	• HTML	• WordPress	
 Illustrator 	• CSS	Print production	
 InDesign 	 jQuery 	Motion design	
• Acrobat	 Bootstrap 	Digital photography	У
Microsoft Office	 Git repos 	 Video production 	

FINE SKILLS

- Brand identity
- Clever responsive layouts
- Digital illustration
- Intuitive mobile UX
- Creative copywriting
- Complex problem solving
- Project organization
- Idea generation
- · Brand strategy
- Traditional illustration

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Advertising & Media – 2010, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, MO
Associate of Fine Arts in Graphic Design – 2007, Saint Louis Community College, St. Louis, MO

EXPERIENCE

Designer/Developer // Rover Enterprises, LLC // March 2014 - April 2016

I created the full design of the RoverTown Mobile Coupon app for iOS and Android, an app that allows customers to show coupons on their smartphone for in-store use, track coupon availability, receive location prompts, compete on leaderboards, and several other extensive features. I also designed a smaller RoverTown for Business app allowing business owners to publish mobile coupons and purchase ad placements.

I designed and hand-coded several corporate websites and landing pages using Bootstrap, WordPress, custom HTML5 and CSS3, and multiple jQuery libraries. I worked closely with web developers to create fully responsive, scalable layouts that can handle variable content.

I created various print materials including a welcome kit for businesses complete with booklet, door sticker, flyers, iBeacons, and instructions inside a custom one-piece folded box. For the final 7 months I oversaw another designer, working together to create print and email marketing assets.

Freelance Designer // McCord Design Group, Fish Window Cleaning // December 2013 - March 2014

I completed a one month contract as an in-office freelancer for McCord Design Group in Kirkwood, MO. I also completed various small projects for Fish Window Cleaning.

Brand Manager // Dover Enterprises, LLC // April 2011 - November 2013

I designed a white-label daily deals platform, including a web and mobile app, called "Groupigg." I created the Dealpigg brand from scratch based on Groupigg. I was responsible for all web and print materials for internal and external use in addition to managing the production of daily deal editorials and light creative copywriting.

In-house Graphic Designer // Fish Window Cleaning Services, Inc. // November 2009 – April 2011

I worked directly with the executive committee in the corporate HQ to create and deliver FISH branding initiatives at the national level, including b2b and consumer marketing materials, product design, vehicle graphics, and more. I created all marketing materials for the franchise sales department. I also provided custom design support to 180 FISH franchisees across 42 states.

Production Artist // JWT Specialized Communications // August 2007 – November 2009

I worked on a small production team that handled a weekly flow of 100-200 newspaper and magazine ads. Other projects included new template creation, photo retouching and internal print projects.